https://policies.uni.edu/web-privacy-statement

Skip to main content
You are hereHome
Web Privacy Statement
Commitment to PrivacyThe University of Northern Iowa (UNI) values individuals' privacy and actively seeks to preserve privacy rights of those who share information with us. Your trust is important to us and we believe you have the right to know how information submitted through the UNI Web site is handled. The following information explains the Internet privacy practices the university has adopted for its official Web sites. In legal terms, however, it shall not be construed as a contractual promise and the university reserves the right to amend it at any time without notice. Privacy and public records obligations of the university are governed by applicable Iowa statutes, including, but not limited to Chapter 22 of the Code of Iowa, and by any applicable U.S. federal laws. The University of Northern Iowa respects the privacy of users visiting our Web sites and will abide by all applicable laws concerning the release of personal information (e.g., Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974).The Information We CollectThe Web Privacy Statement speaks generally to the information collected by or submitted to official UNI Web sites (see the definition above). Since the amount and type of information collected varies from site to site, there may be more specific privacy notices pertaining to the collection and use of personal information associated exclusively with particular pages. Thus it is wise for you to read page-specific notices to ensure you understand the privacy policies and practices applicable to a particular site. When you access official UNI Web pages, certain client information and essential, as well as nonessential technical information (collectively referred to as access information) is automatically collected. No other information is collected through our official Web sites except when you deliberately send it to us (for example, by clicking on a link to send us an e-mail). The Way We Use InformationAs a general rule, UNI does not track individual visitor profiles. We do, however, analyze aggregate traffic and access information for resource management and site planning purposes. UNI reserves the right to use log details to investigate resource management or security concerns. We will never sell or rent your e-mail address or other individual personal information with anyone without your advance permission. Information submitted to us is used to interact with you based on your request for information or continue communications based on a prior relationship.Providing Information is Your ChoiceThere is no legal requirement for you to provide any information at our Web site. Our Web site will not work, however, without routing information and essential technical information. Failure of your browser to provide nonessential technical information will not prevent your use of our Web site but may prevent certain features from working. For any optional information that is requested at our Web site, failure to provide the requested information will mean that the particular feature or service associated with that part of the Web page may not be available to you.Our Commitment To Data SecurityThe University of Northern Iowa is dedicated to taking reasonable precautions in preventing unauthorized data access, maintaining data accuracy, and ensuring the appropriate use of information. We strive to put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial safeguards to secure the information we collect online. These security practices are consistent with the policies of the university and with the laws and regulatory practices of the State of Iowa and the Federal government.How To Contact UsShould you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies and practices, please call University Relations at (319) 273-2761 or send us an e-mail at webteam@uni.edu. If you wish to review or change information gathered about you via an official University of Northern Iowa Web site but you do not know how, University Relations will assist in locating the persons responsible for that site so that you may make your request directly to them.
Search the Policies Site:
Search
